ENDALKACHEW TEDLA

<u>EndalkachewTedla@outlook.com</u> | Flushing, NY (willing to relocate) | +1 347-369-6682 | www.linkedin.com/in/endalkachew-tedla/

DATA ANALYST

Market Research and Product Management Analyst with over two years of professional experience delivering critical insights and facilitating the development of innovative business strategies. Transitioning to the financial services industry after completing the CareerFoundry Data Analytics bootcamp (2024) and acquiring proficiency in Excel, SQL, Python, Tableau, GitHub, and Data Ethics.

KEY SKILLS

- Preparing and Analyzing Data
- Visual Design Tableau
- Databases & SQL

- Python Data Ethics
- Al Machine Learning
- Dashboards

PROFESSIONAL AND WORK EXPERIENCE

Portfolio | https://endalkachew-tedla.github.io/Endalkachew-Tedla-Portfolio/

Student | CareerFoundry Data Analytics Bootcamp | Remote

Jul 2023 - Present

- Data analysis, testing, visualization, dashboarding, querying, etc.
- Tools: Excel, SQL, Python, Tableau, GitHub, Pandas, NumPy, etc.
- Al trends Machine Learning with Python

Product Management Analyst | ShelterPoint Life Insurance | Garden City, NY

Sept 2022 - Jun 2023

- Conducted research and analysis on market conditions to define competitive features or product functions
- Performed industry and product competitive analysis to support product, marketing, and sales strategies
- Offered viable recommendations on study design best practices by building and applying new data analysis modules and data visualization solutions
- Researched and generated Excel QAs and a State Reference Tool
- Tracked external vendor project budget and forecast; produced monthly performance metrics report
- Interacted regularly with marketing, sales, and IT in the development of product implementations, such as Colorado and Oregon PFML

Market Research Analyst | Kantar | New York, NY

Sept 2021 – Jun 2022

- Lead projects through the entire lifecycle, i.e., from proposal to delivery, generating \$3M+ in revenue
- Collaborated with solutions developers, creating automation, saving 120+ hours per quarter
- Proved the value of Kantar's research programs and expertise, selling through and executing an additional \$100k+ YTD in custom studies and solutions
- Designed and programmed surveys to deliver high-quality data, which answered the core business needs of leading companies in the CPG, Pharmaceutical, Telecommunications as well as Food and Beverage industries
- Developed focused, short- and long-term brand and marketing strategies for Fortune 500 companies through custom quantitative and qualitative research to increase their brand equity and market share
- Strategized in coordination with the Chief Client Officer to improve regional client and office engagement

EDUCATION

2017

Bachelor of Science (BS) Business Administration | Binghamton University School of Management | Binghamton, NY

Concentration in Management Information Systems, GPA 3.7